MARIANNE GAA

mariannegaa@gmail.com (438) 777-4887

Toronto, Ontario Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

PROFILE

Academic background in statistics, research and project design. Self-taught programmer through Udemy and Codecademy coursework, StackOverflow resources, and a lot of trial and error. Resilient to frustration, detail-oriented and inspired by challenging problems. Bilingual in English and French. Looking to break into a **Data Analyst** (or related) role.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Excel, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python Programming, Automation, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Statistics, Data Visualization, Jupyter Notebooks, Tableau, Git, Github and Command Line.

EDUCATION

GradCert International Development, Humber College, 2017 Toronto BA Psychology, Brock University, 2014 St. Catharines

CERTIFICATES

Excel from Beginner to Advanced, Udemy, 2020

MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence, Udemy, 2020

Automate the Boring Stuff with Python Programming, Udemy, 2020

EXPERIENCE

Kampai Garden, Hostess, 2018 — 2019 Montreal

- Client-facing role in a fast-paced environment, responsible for promptly addressing all guest requests and concerns, with a proven ability to multitask
- Coordinated a diverse team to reduce turnaround time between services to 15 minutes in order to maximize capacity and business

West Africa Network for Peace Building, Reporting & Communications Assistant, 2017 — 2018 Ghana

- Relationship building within the community through strategic communications
- Designed communications for distribution in collaboration with the Plan International team, expanding reach of conflict prevention programs to Ghana's youth demographic
- Summarization of key insights of projects and activities for the National Director and partner organization, The Fund for Peace
- Contributed to the organization's Annual Report 2016 and provided regional updates on conflicts within Ghana's mining communities for the National Action Plan 2018

HRG Inc., Customer Service Representative, 2014 — 2016 Montreal

- Very technical and detail oriented role, exchanging airfare through back end software which required excellent problem solving in challenging situations
- Proven track record for eliminating surcharges from airlines by heeding airfare exchange rules meticulously
- Exceptional statistics related to call handing and efficiency
- Responsible for troubleshooting online tools for clients and streamlining process for utilizing company products